# Yusuf Eko Anggoro

### **Back-End Developer**

Jakarta | +62 859 3453 1182 | anggoroekoyusuf@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

A back-end developer with 3+ years of experience building, developing, implementing **Test Driven Development**, and maintaining. I really enjoy learning new things, especially about the latest technology. My current back-end language is **PHP**, **JavaScript** and **Golang**.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### PT Telkom Indonesia – Jakarta, Indonesia

Back-End Developer (August 2019 - present)

- Building, developing, implementing **Test Driven Development**, analysis and maintaining **microservices** architecture such as gamification service, ticket service, notification service, user service and worker service. **RESTful APIs** or **Apache Kafka** function as the glue that integrates the **microservices** into application.
- Skill in reading technical documentation and back-end integration with third-parties.
- Utilitized **OpenShift** to configure and deploy applications.
- Worked on NoSQL and SQL databases like MongoDB and Oracle.
- Experience with container-based deployment using **Jenkins** and **Docker**.
- Used Apache Kafka for Publish/Subscribe pattern in applications dealing with messaging.
- Used **GIT** for version control.
- Experience in **Agile** Development process with Atlassian Jira.
- Implementing best practices.
- With caching (Redis), ELK stack (Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana).
- Used MinIO for enterprise file storage.
- Used FCM for notifications.

### Coding Bootcamp Arkademy - Jakarta, Indonesia

Full-Stack Developer (July 2019 - August 2019)

• Arkademy is a software engineering program that provides a 6 weeks hands-on coding curriculum that focuses on mobile development with react native and node JS.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Indraprasta PGRI University (2020 - 2024)

Bachelor of Information Technology - Coming Soon

## Vocational High School 24 Jakarta (2017 - 2019)

Learn and explore all the ways of software development including making software, maintenance, software development organization management and quality management. Not only that, I also learned computer software from making websites, applications and everything related programming by mastering the programming language.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

• Ekipa Indonesia Scrum Master 1

# **SKILLS**

- **Programming Languages:** PHP, JavaScript, Golang
- Back-end Technologies: Express.js, Golang, Laravel
- Web Technologies: HTML, JavaScript, CSS, React, Typescript, Laravel, CodeIgniter
- **Development Tools (IDEs):** Visual Studio Code

- Version Control: GIT
- **RDBMS:** MySQL, Oracle
- NoSQL: MongoDB
- **Platforms:** Windows, Linux
- **Methodologies:** Agile and Waterfall Methodology
- Build Tools: Jenkins CI/CD